<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>

    <!--__________ Player Faction Definitions __________-->

    <!-- Brotherhood of Steel Player Faction -->

    <FactionDef ParentName="PlayerFactionBase">
        <defName>FCP_Faction_BoS_Player</defName>
        <label>Brotherhood of Steel</label>
        <description>The Brotherhood of Steel is one of the oldest still existing factions in the wasteland. It was founded just before and during the great war itself. True to its army origin, the Brotherhood is a militarised society, based on discipline, prowess, and reliability. However, there are a great number of Brotherhood chapters with often strongly deviating philosophies. Some might see themselves as the sole protectors of humanity and act noble and chivalrous, while others might see outsiders as clueless degenerates unfit for the technological marvels they might possess. Among the few things shared by all chapters of the Brotherhood is their obsession with technology (and the safeguarding of it) and their imposing suits of power armour which make them, despite their small numbers, one of the most powerful groups in the wasteland.</description>
        <isPlayer>true</isPlayer>
        <classicIdeo>true</classicIdeo>
        <techLevel>Industrial</techLevel>
        <basicMemberKind>FCP_Pawnkind_BoS_Knight_Player</basicMemberKind>
        <pawnSingular>Brother</pawnSingular>
        <pawnsPlural>Brothers</pawnsPlural>
        <leaderTitle>Elder</leaderTitle>
        <factionIconPath>World_Icon/BoS_Icon/FCP_BoS_World_Icon</factionIconPath>
        <colorSpectrum>
			<li>(1, 1, 1)</li>
        </colorSpectrum>
        <allowedCultures>
            <li>FCP_Culture_BoS</li>
        </allowedCultures>
        <backstoryFilters>
            <li>
                <categories>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS_Child</li>
                </categories>
            </li>
        </backstoryFilters>
    </FactionDef>

    <!-- Lyons Pride Remnants Player Faction -->

    <FactionDef ParentName="PlayerFactionBase">
        <defName>FCP_Faction_BoS_Lyons_Pride_Remnants_Player</defName>
        <label>Lyons' Pride Remnants</label>
        <description>The Lyons' Pride remnants are a faction of disciplined and technologically advanced warriors, striving to preserve the ideals of their late leader, Elder Lyons. Once a proud and unified chapter, they now operate as a fragmented yet determined group, clinging to their mission of protecting humanity and safeguarding advanced technology. Though their numbers have dwindled, their resolve remains unshaken, and they continue to uphold their code of honor amidst the chaos of the wasteland. Their advanced weaponry, power armor, and tactical expertise make them a formidable force, whether as allies or adversaries.</description>
        <isPlayer>true</isPlayer>
        <classicIdeo>true</classicIdeo>
        <techLevel>Industrial</techLevel>
        <basicMemberKind>FCP_Pawnkind_Lyons_Pride_Knight_Player</basicMemberKind>
        <pawnSingular>Brother</pawnSingular>
        <pawnsPlural>Brothers</pawnsPlural>
        <leaderTitle>Elder</leaderTitle>
        <factionIconPath>World_Icon/BoS_Icon/FCP_Lyons_Pride_Remnants_World_Icon</factionIconPath>
        <colorSpectrum>
			<li>(1, 1, 1)</li>
        </colorSpectrum>
        <allowedCultures>
            <li>FCP_Culture_Lyons_BoS</li>
        </allowedCultures>
        <backstoryFilters>
            <li>
                <categories>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Lyons_BoS</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Lyons_Child</li>
                </categories>
            </li>
        </backstoryFilters>
    </FactionDef>

    <!-- Brotherhood Outcasts Player Faction -->

    <FactionDef ParentName="PlayerFactionBase">
        <defName>FCP_Faction_BoS_Outcast_Remnants_Player</defName>
        <label>Brotherhood Outcasts</label>
        <description>The Outcast Remnants are a hardened splinter group of the Brotherhood of Steel, formed by those who rejected the Brotherhood's changing ideals and chose to uphold the original mission: the recovery and preservation of advanced technology at any cost. Isolated from their former brothers, the Outcasts are fiercely independent, pragmatic, and often distrustful of outsiders. Their camps are fortified, their patrols relentless, and their loyalty to their cause unwavering. Though their numbers are few, their discipline, technical expertise, and mastery of power armor make them a formidable force in the wasteland.</description>
        <isPlayer>true</isPlayer>
        <classicIdeo>true</classicIdeo>
        <techLevel>Industrial</techLevel>
        <basicMemberKind>FCP_Pawnkind_BoS_Outcast_Defeneder_Player</basicMemberKind>
        <pawnSingular>Outcast</pawnSingular>
        <pawnsPlural>Outcasts</pawnsPlural>
        <leaderTitle>Protector</leaderTitle>
        <factionIconPath>World_Icon/BoS_Icon/FCP_Outcast_World_Icon</factionIconPath>
        <colorSpectrum>
			<li>(1, 1, 1)</li>
        </colorSpectrum>
        <allowedCultures>
            <li>FCP_Culture_BoS_Outcasts</li>
        </allowedCultures>
        <backstoryFilters>
            <li>
                <categories>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Outcast_Defender</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Outcast_Specialist</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Outcast_Recon</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Outcasts</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_Outcasts_Child</li>
                </categories>
            </li>
        </backstoryFilters>
    </FactionDef>

    <!-- Brotherhood of Steel Mojave Chapter Player Faction -->

    <FactionDef ParentName="PlayerFactionBase">
        <defName>FCP_Faction_BoS_Mojave_Player</defName>
        <label>Mojave Chapter</label>
        <description>The Mojave Chapter of the Brotherhood of Steel is a shadow of its former self, forced out of the Hidden Valley bunker and now struggling to survive in the harsh Mojave wasteland. Once a proud and disciplined force, they have been reduced to a scattered group, clinging to their mission of safeguarding humanity's technological heritage. Despite their diminished state, their mastery of power armor and energy weapons ensures they remain a formidable presence in the region.</description>
        <isPlayer>true</isPlayer>
        <classicIdeo>true</classicIdeo>
        <techLevel>Industrial</techLevel>
        <basicMemberKind>FCP_Pawnkind_BoS_Mojave_Knight_Player</basicMemberKind>
        <pawnSingular>Brother</pawnSingular>
        <pawnsPlural>Brothers</pawnsPlural>
        <leaderTitle>Elder</leaderTitle>
        <factionIconPath>World_Icon/BoS_Icon/FCP_Mojave_World_Icon</factionIconPath>
        <colorSpectrum>
			<li>(1, 1, 1)</li>
        </colorSpectrum>
        <allowedCultures>
            <li>FCP_Culture_BoS</li>
        </allowedCultures>
        <backstoryFilters>
            <li>
                <categories>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS_Mojave</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS_Mojave_Child</li>
                </categories>
            </li>
        </backstoryFilters>
    </FactionDef>

    <!-- Brotherhood of Steel Appalachia Chapter Player Faction -->

    <FactionDef ParentName="PlayerFactionBase">
        <defName>FCP_Faction_BoS_Appalachia_Player</defName>
        <label>Appalachia Chapter</label>
        <description>The Appalachia Chapter stands at a crossroads. Cut off from Lost Hills and forced to operate independently, you must decide your chapter's path: will you follow "The Chain That Binds" - the strict Codex doctrine that demands technological preservation above all else? Or will you break from tradition and become protectors of the wasteland's people, proving the Brotherhood can be more than collectors? Your isolation means no oversight, no reinforcements, but complete freedom to define what the Brotherhood truly stands for in these lands.</description>
        <isPlayer>true</isPlayer>
        <classicIdeo>true</classicIdeo>
        <techLevel>Industrial</techLevel>
        <basicMemberKind>FCP_Pawnkind_BoS_Knight_Player</basicMemberKind>
        <pawnSingular>Brother</pawnSingular>
        <pawnsPlural>Brothers</pawnsPlural>
        <leaderTitle>Paladin</leaderTitle>
        <factionIconPath>World_Icon/BoS_Icon/FCP_Appalaccia_World_Icon</factionIconPath>
        <colorSpectrum>
			<li>(1, 1, 1)</li>
        </colorSpectrum>
        <allowedCultures>
            <li>FCP_Culture_BoS</li>
        </allowedCultures>
        <backstoryFilters>
            <li>
                <categories>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS</li>
                    <li>FCP_Backstory_BoS_Child</li>
                </categories>
            </li>
        </backstoryFilters>
    </FactionDef>

</Defs>